Japanese phonograph record collection, circa 1927-1932
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Japanese phonograph record collection
circa 1927-1932
C0141
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
0.25 linear feet (1 box)
The Japanese phonograph record collection contains 15 78 rpm phonograph records mostly in sleeves with Japanese writing. The records were either printed in the United States or Japan for the Japanese music market, and released by Columbia, Ploydor, Victor, Orient Records and Regal.
Historical Information
The records in this collection are early examples of "electrical" recordings. Prior to 1925 recordings were made acoustically with singers and musicians playing into a horn. Electrical recording introduced the microphone which could pick up a larger range of sound and tone. Record companies developed specific names for this new recording process. The Victor Talking Machine company dubbed the new electric records as Othrophonic Records; Columbia produced "viva-tonal" records. The records in this collection are labeled as such.
A product of Nipponophone, Orient was acquired by Columbia in 1925
Scope and Contents
The Japanese phonograph record collection contains 15 78 rpm phonograph records produced for sale in Japan. The collection also includes original record sleeves and printed material packaged with the record. The records in this collection were released by: Columbia, Regal, Victor, Ploydor and Orient Records. The records could have been released by the American division of these labels for export, or by there Japanese branches. The design of the labels present on the discs indicated that these records were released in the late 1920s through early 1930s. The records have been recorded with the new "electric" recording process, which was introduced to the music industry in 1925.
The song title and artist name are printed in Japanese with only the record company name printed in English. As of now the records remain unidentified.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the Music, Theatre, and Spoken Word sound recording collection.
Arrangement
Organized into five series.
Series 1: Columbia, circa 1928 (Box 1)
Series 2: Victor, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1)
Series 3: Orient, circa 1928 (Box 1)
Series 4: Ploydor, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1)
Series 5: Columbia Regal, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1)
Acquisition Information
Donor unknown.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Music--20th century.; Music--Japan; Music--Japan--20th century; Music.
Document Types:
Sound recordings.
Contents List
- Series 1: Columbia, circa 1928 (Box 1)
  - Columbia 26507, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Columbia 26508, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Victor, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1)
  - Victor 50833, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Victor 50834, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Victor 50834, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Victor 50604, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Victor 50605, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Victor 50833, circa 1927-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Orient, circa 1928 (Box 1)
  - Orient 60433, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Orient 60432, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 4: Polydor, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1)
  - Polydor 3832, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Polydor 3833, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series 5: Columbia Regal, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1)
  - Columbia Regal 65882, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Columbia Regal 65883, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Record Sleeves, circa 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)